<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Researches on Yao&#39;s GithubPage</title>
    <link>https://yaolei-leo.github.io/research/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Researches on Yao&#39;s GithubPage</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://yaolei-leo.github.io/research/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Common variants GWAS analysis in Systemic lupus erythematosus (SLE)</title>
      <link>https://yaolei-leo.github.io/research/sle_gwas/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://yaolei-leo.github.io/research/sle_gwas/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;SLE is a complex autoimmune disease with high genetic heretabilty. Prof. Wanling Yang&amp;rsquo;s group is dedicated to the genomic and transcriptomic research of SLE. During my study in Prof. Yang&amp;rsquo;s lab, I have been involved in mutlitple projects of SLE common variants GWAS analysis.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Transcriptomic analysis of kidney transplant fibrosis</title>
      <link>https://yaolei-leo.github.io/research/scrna_kidneytransplant/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://yaolei-leo.github.io/research/scrna_kidneytransplant/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Chronic kidney disease (CKD) is a major public health issue, and kidney transplantation is the most effective treatment for end-stage renal disease. However, the long-term success of kidney transplantation is often hindered by chronic allograft dysfunction (CAD), which is characterized by progressive fibrosis in the transplanted kidney. Understanding the molecular mechanisms underlying CAD is crucial for improving transplant outcomes.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Rare variant whole-genome sequencing analysis in Systemic lupus erythematosus (SLE)</title>
      <link>https://yaolei-leo.github.io/research/sle_wgs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://yaolei-leo.github.io/research/sle_wgs/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;SLE is a complex autoimmune disease with high genetic heretabilty. Although many common variants have been identified in SLE, the contribution of rare variants to SLE pathogenesis remains largely unexplored. Genetic heritability analysis shown that the contribution of currentyl identified common variants is limited. Therefore, we performed a whole-genome sequencing (WGS) analysis of SLE patients to identify rare variants associated with SLE.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
